

# Matěj Frič

#### **Contact Info**

- in linkedin.com/in/matej-fric
- github.com/matejfric
- Iinktr.ee/matejfric

### Languages

Czech
English
German

#### **Hobbies**













# **Projects**

- **1** Bachelor thesis
- Corrosion segmentation
- Redis in-memory database
- 器 Neural network from scratch

#### **Miscellaneous**

Driving license category B

#### About

With a background in Computational and Applied Mathematics from VŠB-TUO, I focus primarily on machine learning and computer vision. During my academic journey, I participated in research on Bayesian models for corrosion segmentation, which resulted in my bachelor thesis, *Scalable Probabilistic Approximation Method in Applications*. I am currently working on my master's thesis titled *In-Vehicle Driver State Analysis Using Image Segmentation*.

## **Education**

September 2020 − Present • Ostrava

## **VSB - Technical University of Ostrava**

- Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science
- BSc Computational and Applied Mathematics
- MS Computer Science Data Analysis and Processing

June 2022 • Charles University, Poděbrady

### **Summer Language School - Sommerkolleg 2022**

• German for moderately advanced (B1)

September 2012 – June 2020 ♥ Ostrava

#### Matiční Grammar School Ostrava

# **Experience**

June 2023 – Present ♥ Ostrava

#### Data Scientist - Stora Enso

- Developed machine learning models for forestry applications \$\rightarrow\$ using geospatial datasets \$\rightarrow\$, including satellite imagery \$\rightarrow\$
- Built computer vision solutions for industrial use cases
- Collaborated within an international team of data scientists

August 2022 – June 2024 ♥ Ostrava

## Junior Researcher - VSB-TUO

Bayesian methods for corrosion segmentation

June 2019 – August 2024 ♀ Ostrava

Shop Assistant - Kolovna Koncept, s.r.o.

June 2018 – July 2018 ♥ Kopřivnice

#### **Quality Controller - Röchling Automotive**

#### □ Skills

Python
Al/ML

MS-SQL, PL-SQL Azure Tensorflow/Pytorch

🖐 Docker 💮 Databricks Apache Spark

♦ Git 🔞 Rust 🗠 🗗 EX